This is a video that I wish someone had
made for me when I was a bit younger.
And I'm going to cover off where I think
the best place to invest is, why you don't
actually need loads of cash to start
investing in the first place,
and why I think
so many people are still overlooking one
of the best places to invest.
Now, this is not financial advice.
I'm not even financially literate,
and I've never really been interested
in any of the traditional means of
investing.
And come the end of this video,
you're either going to feel slightly
motivated with
a pep talk,
or you're going to think I'm the biggest
idiot you've ever seen on
YouTube. Now, the first thing
that I think is a big problem
is the amount we're
told you need to invest, you need to save,
you need to be squirreling money away.
Now, hold on. For the majority of my life,
I was struggling to get by.
You've got the money you earn,
which you've got to pay tax on,
then you've got to
use some money to enjoy yourself,
because if you don't enjoy yourself now in
a bid
to enjoy yourself later,
you might just spend the next 10,
15 years being miserable
saving money to then not even be able to
enjoy it.
And I know this is a bit morbid, but
when I was growing up, there
was a girl in my
local area who didn't go on holiday for
three or four years, and she was the first
out of all of her friends to buy a house.
And about a year and a half after moving
in, she got cancer and died.
So we need to appreciate there
is an element of risk.
If you're going to save up
and squirrel all of your money to
retirement, you're
making a bet that you're 100% going to
make it there.
And the majority of people probably will.
And as a man, statistically,
the thing that's most likely to kill you
before retirement is yourself. So again,
we definitely need to enjoy
ourselves and not just say,
"Let's wait till we're 60 or 65
to be happy in life." It's the biggest con
ever.
So the majority of people watching this,
you're getting gaslit from people all
around you telling you to invest,
but you're like, "Invest what?
After I've enjoyed myself a little bit
and paid tax on my income, there's barely
anything left." Taxes are crazy,
and because of inflation and tax brackets
staying in the same place,
even with salaries going up, people
are just getting
bumped into the next tax bracket.
Not to mention there are other costs
that my
generation and probably your generation
have grown up with, whether it's student
loans where student debt used to be free,
or the first price of a
flipping house. Sydney, Australia
is the second-worst place in the world
behind
Hong Kong.
You're looking at over ten times average
salary to get
yourself on the property ladder here.
London, cooked.
I know there are some places in the world
not as bad, but I've had a lot of
arguments with my parents,
and they're like, "Oh, but inflation
was a lot higher
when we were younger." I was like, "Yeah,
but Mom, Dad, 15% inflation on a
house that's only two
and a half times salary
is a different deal." But we're not
here to have baby boomers versus
millennials in a fight.
Now, one thing you've probably seen
that is driving me mad
is the crypto bros. Now,
going to put this out there.
My understanding of crypto maybe isn't
that advanced.
Maybe I am naive and ignorant,
and honestly, if you are a
crypto expert,
please correct me in the comments, and
if you're really clued
up about this world,
I would happily debate you on a podcast.
Happily.
Now, the reason I think
that cryptocurrencies
are so popular for young people is
any route that they have to financial
freedom or having a nice
house or having the luxury of spare income
isn't going to come from
their traditional means. They go, "Oh,
if I get this job, which is in line for my
age and the pay for my age and experience,
oh, I'd have to work
at that company for 35 years,
saving everything I earn after tax to
afford a McLaren." No.
They look at something else and they go,
"Okay.
Well,
I'd have to invest all the money I have
into the S&P 500, and then maybe in
15, 20 years,
I could afford a deposit." No.
So when the option's in front of you
are limited, crypto seems like an
appealing option to go with.
Think of it like this.
Have you ever heard of something called
the small town plus two?
I used to play rugby in the South Island
of New Zealand in a place called Oamaru.
I wouldn't recommend it. It was cold,
I came back with facial hair, and we had
penguins. But the point that I found
was there were no attractive girls in
Oamaru.
So it was only after a long amount of time
that you spend there, there was this
phenomenon called the small town plus two,
where a 6 out of 10 would become an 8
out of 10 very quickly.
The only other place
that we could even say this exists is
within the workplace.
You might work in an office,
and I remember, you'd
catch a glimpse of someone from HR.
She's a five at best, but in the office,
she's a seven.
And when we're looking at the
opportunities around us financially for
investments,
crypto wouldn't be that appealing
if young people had other options
to potentially buy something
and watch it go up.
The issue I have with crypto is this.
People say it's a currency, and if it
was a currency being used as a currency, I
could maybe understand it,
but people actually
are buying a currency as an
investment,
which is just an interesting way to look
at it.
And as economic times get worse
and people get more desperate
and people buy into
it, I get it. The price of Bitcoin
is now at $100,000.
But I can't help but think this
is just a complex Ponzi scheme.
And again, if I'm wrong,
tell me I'm wrong.
But if we look at, was it Bernie Madoff?
The guy who would just take people's money
as an investment and pay the people that
were there earlier,
so then more people came,
more people gave him money.
Then he paid the second tier of people
that got there early, and basically,
he was
just using new money to pay previous
investors.
And if we look at people in the Bitcoin
world, it is the early investors that are
making cash off the new investors'
investment.
Now,
it could be a currency that's ended up
being used and whatever, but it's been
like 13 years, and it's just not
that well integrated unless
you're a drug dealer. Drug dealer?
And this is my other gripe with it.
Everyone that's holding it right now--
Well, actually, first of all,
if anyone's in
crypto, first of all, they're like, "Oh,
you need to buy. You need to buy.
You need to buy." But if I buy,
your coins now become worth more,
so you're
kind of financially incentivized to tell
me to buy.
Then they have terms like,
"Hold on for dear life." Kind of
gaslighting their
audience. Never sell, because again,
if you sell, you could potentially start a
cascade of people selling. But this
is the thing, right?
So everyone out there, let's say,
has a price.
So all these people holding Bitcoin right
now, it's $100,000.
When that gets to an amount, on average,
that people could exit their
investment and have a meaningful impact on
their family, people will exit.
Think of it this way.
Whatever your crypto portfolio is now,
if that reached like 5
million US dollars,
no matter how much you believe in crypto,
the future, and it
going to the moon and being worth more,
part of you is going to go, "Jesus, if I
sell everything, I can just do a runner,
abandon the community, buy my family a
house,
and put my kids through private
education," or whatever it is.
Human greed only goes so far,
and eventually, I feel the Ponzi scheme
is going to
get to a point where everyone's just going
to take their cash and run.
It's all going to come crumbling down.
It's not often people give you advice
unless it benefits them. Even this video.
By giving you the advice
that I'm about to give you a little bit
later on in this
video, this benefits me, because
if you buy into my system,
some of you will end up
joining my course. But at least
if you were to join-In my course,
you would have
tools and knowledge
that you could use to keep compounding
your investment, which
I'll get onto in a second.
But even this week,
we saw the Hawk Tuah coin
pumped and dumped. Everyone's pumping
and dumping, whether it's Andrew Tate,
Hawk
Tuah, Logan Paul. With these shit coins,
meme coins, everyone's
just hyping, hyping, hyping,
then doing a rug pull.
And history keeps repeating itself,
and everyone's going, "No,
but it's different
with my coin." I could be wrong,
but I just do not think that crypto
is a good
investment. And here's another thing.
I had to sack a member of staff because he
was too obsessed with it.
It's all he would talk about. And I said,
"Do you know what, mate?
You're never going to be great at what you
do for a living because you genuinely
believe that your coin's going to make you
rich." And that's a problem.
I used to live with a guy who
was a stripper. He was a good stripper.
He used to make $1,000 a weekend
stripping.
I said to him,
"You're never going to be a fantastic
coach." And he said, "Why?" I
said, "Because you don't need to be.
Because that little bit of cash
that you're making on the side from
stripping is
preventing you from being a great coach."
Same way that these people that maybe
have slumps in their business performance,
they go, "It's okay, because my
XRP coin is going to go to the moon next
year, and I'm going to be rich." These
lies that you tell yourself
are actually damaging your position in the
short term.
But this isn't a crypto video. Now,
when it comes to traditional investments,
like
taking spare cash that you have
and putting it into the S&P 500, cool.
Yeah.
But again, the compounding impact of that,
you've just got to keep putting it in
for years and years and years
and years and years.
And then again, people are like, "Oh,
you'll be rich when you're 50 or 60." And
it's very difficult as a young person to
appreciate that.
You're like, "Yeah, cool," but I'm like,
"I'm 35, brother.
I don't want to wait 20 years to have a
Porsche 911.
I kind of want one in the next few years."
So people look to more volatile
industries like crypto or gambling.
They're putting their accumulators on
their football bets at the weekend, just
hoping that Sunderland come through with a
4-nil win and get their accumulator to
the moon. But the issue with gambling
is that even though some people do often
win
big, behind the scenes,
there's a lot of losses.
Even people that do win big in gambling,
they think, "Well, I made that much money
gambling,
I should probably gamble a bit more
and make it more." Now, a lot of you
that have followed me for a
while will know that I had to take a bit
of a
hypocritical stance
when it came to property investment.
I always said that I never wanted a
mortgage, never wanted to buy a house,
and I
bought a house.
But the kind of stance I had
is I just don't see it quite as
the investment that most people do.
The reason being is, first of all,
you should not be using the fact you
bought a
house as a metric of success,
dangling your key in front of the house.
Because a lot of you, not all of you,
a lot of you sometimes can be
saving money through what could be the
best years of your life to partner
and move
into a house with a partner, especially
if you buy in your early 20s.
Not many of you do it on your own.
You do it in a relationship because then
you get
to split the deposit,
split the repayments,
everything like that.
And who you are in your early 20s isn't
often who you are in your older 20s.
So a lot of couples do go their separate
ways.
So you end up buying a house with someone
you didn't really love, and you often buy
in an area that you didn't really want to
live in, which means that you often have
to commute quite a bit further to work,
which makes the experience of going to
work
that little bit less enjoyable.
Then you create a little prison for
yourself that
when your relationship doesn't start
working out,
you're kind of financially and
physically tied to that person,
which can cause all kinds of instability
in a
relationship. Put it this way,
a lot of people bought houses with people
they don't
love to live in an area they didn't want
to live in, and now they're stuck working
a job that they might not be loving
because they've got to pay the mortgage.
Again, like I said, that's not everyone,
but for some people, they go, "Fucking
hell, he's right." And again,
for those of you
that maybe do have the spare income
to buy, if you're going to buy it,
buy it for security. That's why I bought.
I have a dog. He likes the beach.
There was a house. It was near the beach.
So if I do this,
I don't have to worry about the rental
market going crazy or
whatever. But I wouldn't say this house
is an investment.
The stamp duty is cooked you've got to pay
on a house, especially a nice one.
Cheers, have 100 grand. Thanks. Oh,
how do I pay for that?
With money that I've already paid tax on?
Lovely.
And if I want to move house again, oh,
just pay stamp duty again.
Oh,
but you don't have to pay capital gains
because it's the house that you live
in. Cool,
but I've still already paid tax on this
money. You already got half.
Now you're going to penalize me six
figures every time I move.
Make that make sense.
Not to mention you got upkeep of the
property,
insurance, bills, maintenance.
And then some people go, "Oh,
but my property in the last five years has
gone up by
£150,000." Has it? Or
is your money worth less?
Because the buying power's gone.
And even if you sit there and go,
"My property
went up by 20% in value," well,
guess what?
The property you're moving into
is going up by 20% in value.
And everyone says, "Ah, but renting
is wasting money." Do you know what else
is
wasting money? Paying stamp duty.
Oh,
you're just pissing away £1,000 a month.
Well,
you might have to give fucking 60 grand to
the government if you next want to
move house, change postcode. Now,
that's not to say that the property
industry isn't lucrative. But again,
I think it can distract people
away from other potential means of making
money, which I'm getting into now.
I never really cared about any of this
stuff. I didn't.
And to be honest, I still don't.
I don't hold any crypto.
I don't have any money invested in the S&P
500 or in ETFs.
My investment portfolio
is technically at zero,
but technically also not at
zero.
There was an interest savings account
that I was very interested in in an
earlier stage of life, almost by accident.
And at 24,
instead of trying to buy a house
or instead of trying to get crypto or
instead of trying to do any of these
things,
I decided my interest savings account
was going to be an audience.
And I knew that I could pay into
that interest
savings account every time I created a
piece of content.
So every time I made a reel,
every time I made a tweet,
every time I wrote an
email,
I was in essence not just paying into my
interest savings account,
but I was being able to impact it on a
daily or even hourly
basis.
Whereas if you put something in the S&P
500, you've got to sit
back and wait for ages.
When you look to build an audience,
you are in control of
that investment fully, wholly.
You have a video
that outperforms all the other
videos, your share prices go up,
and it can impact your business.
I can see on a day-by-day basis the
financial position of my
business is impacted by paying in,
just like I am now with this
video. And for a lot of young people,
and again,
not everyone has what it takes to
build an audience, post for years,
create a business, serve people online,
whatever
it is, but for a lot of people, you do.
Now, similarly to a lot of investments,
if you put money in in the first year,
you're not going to see a massive amount
of that.
But in social media, 100% you could.
And there are people, even in my program,
that are thinking about going to uni and
doing a master's, and I'm like, "Cool,
you can spend a year or several years
becoming better educated, and
if you're a doctor or a surgeon
or you're flying a
plane, cool." But if you
were to spend those four years instead
making better content,
producing YouTube videos,
learning how to use Photoshop for
thumbnails,
you can drastically impact the level
and quality of your life and the
people around you.
And no one's really had
that opportunity before.
And the compounding effect of an audience
Can be drastic.
And again, sure, there
is the survivorship bias.
I'm only giving this advice because I
posted content and it worked for me.
But again,
you don't need to have millions of
followers and hundreds of thousands
of people. For so many of you, even
if the content just makes a meaningful
impact to the traffic, to your business,
or to your shop, or to your online
English lessons, or your jujitsu gym,
whatever it is.
Gary Vee calls it day trading attention,
which is what it is.
The most valuable commodity to me isn't
shares.
It's not stocks, it's not crypto,
it's attention.
And over the years,
I'm trying to master the art of capturing
people's attention
and accruing goodwill with that audience,
so that ultimately, if I can give enough
value to someone,
we're going to come to a point where
eventually they go, "I'm
in." And I can't believe so many people
are sleeping on this opportunity.
Are you going to become a millionaire
and have a McLaren? Maybe, maybe not.
But for the first time in history,
if you master the art of making good
content and
helping people with their thinking,
every video should give someone like an
aha
moment. Or even with this,
it'd be nice for someone to go, "I
was kind of stumped
before with the idea of investment,
but now I realize that
if I can get a camera, a
microphone, or even just use my phone
and learn how to edit, I can start my
portfolio and I can start growing it over
the next few years." And the more
aggressive you want to grow it,
the better.
In the early days, I
was going live every single day at 5:00 AM
in the morning
before work.
Everything in life kind of works out the
same.
The more you put in, the more you get out.
But not so many investments
are malleable and in a
way that you can impact them as creating
an audience and having some kind
of business associated to it.
So for any of you out there that
are younger and
you're ambitious and you're kind of
worried about where you should be
investing,
start building now.
You might not take a dividend for a few
years, but where
everything out there
is potentially dodgy and unsafe
and volatile, it's almost
one of the safest investments ever.
And what do you need?
Even if you were to start your investment
with $1,000, camera,
tripod, laptop, edit, happy days.
If you've got the solution to people's
problems, you can create a business out of
it.
And I think if you truly want to get rich
in this day and age, which really
should mean just having more money than
you need. Do you know what being rich is?
Going to dinner and not worrying about
what things cost. That's it.
Going to dinner and knowing
that you can just put your card down
and pay for your
friends. That's rich.
Everything after that is just bullshit.
I think that's what Joe Rogan says,
anyway.
That's what I want you to see investing.
And the better you can do that,
the more you can start allocating your
effort into
manipulating the market, and
that market being your audience.
I'll put some links in the description
if you want to learn how to do that more,
but if not,
I'll see you in the next video.
YouTube will probably put a thumbnail here
of a video it thinks that you'll enjoy,
so maybe click that,
see what you think of that one as well.
See you in a bit.
Bye-bye.